This is the exact moment
هذه اللحظة بالضبط
that I started creating something called Tinkering School.
التي بدأت فيها إنشاء شئ يسمى مدرسة التصليح
Tinkering School is a place where kids can pick up sticks
مدرسة التصليح هي المكان الذي يمكن للأطفال فيه أخذ عصى
and hammers and other dangerous objects,
ومطارق وغيرها من الأشياء الخطرة
and be trusted.
ونثق بهم
Trusted not to hurt themselves,
نثق بهم أن لا يأذوا أنفسهم
and trusted not to hurt others.
ونثق بهم أن لا يأذوا الآخرين
Tinkering School doesn't follow a set curriculum,
مدرسة التصليح لا تتبع مجموعة من المناهج
and there are no tests.
وليس هناك إختبارات
We're not trying to teach anybody any specific thing.
لا نحاول تعليم أي شخص شيئاً محدداً
When the kids arrive
عندما يصل الأطفال
they're confronted with lots of stuff:
تجابههم العديد من الأشياء
wood and nails and rope and wheels,
خشب ومسامير وحبال وإطارات
and lots of tools, real tools.
والكثير الكثير من الأدوات، أدوات حقيقية
It's a six-day immersive experience for the kids.
أنها تجربة ستة أيام غامرة للأطفال
And within that context, we can offer the kids time --
وفي ذلك السياق، يمكننا تقديم الوقت للأطفال
something that seems in short supply
شيئاً يبدو قليلاً في المعروض
in their over-scheduled lives.
في حياتهم المليئة بالأشغال
Our goal is to ensure that they leave
هدفنا هو التأكد من أنهم سيغادروا
with a better sense of how to make things
مع إحساس أفضل لكيفية صنع الأشياء
than when they arrived,
عن وقت وصولهم
and the deep internal realization
والتصديق الداخلي العميق
that you can figure things out by fooling around.
بأنه يمكنك معرفة الأشياء المحيطة بالتدرب
Nothing ever turns out as planned ... ever.
لا شئ يمضي كما هو مخطط له...بتاتاً
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And the kids soon learn
وسرعان ما يتعلم الأطفال
that all projects go awry --
أن كل المشاريع فشلت-ـ
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
and become at ease with the idea that every step
وأصبحت على وفاق مع الفكرة القائلة بأن كل خطوة
in a project is a step closer
في المشروع هي خطوة أقرب
to sweet success,
للنجاح الجميل
or gleeful calamity.
أو بهجة الكارثة
We start from doodles and sketches.
نبدأ من الرسومات والمقاطع
And sometimes we make real plans.
وبعض الأحيان نصنع خطط حقيقية
And sometimes we just start building.
وبعض الأحيان نبدأ مباشرة بالبناء
Building is at the heart of the experience:
البناء يكمن في قلب التجربة
hands on, deeply immersed
الأيادي تعمل، غارقة
and fully committed to the problem at hand.
وملتزمة تماماً بالمشكلة محل النظر
Robin and I, acting as collaborators,
أنا وروبين، نعمل كمشاركين
keep the landscape of the projects
نحفظ مكان المشاريع
tilted towards completion.
بإستمالة نحو الإكمال
Success is in the doing,
النجاح في العمل
and failures are celebrated and analyzed.
والفشل مرُحب به ويتم تحليله
Problems become puzzles
المشاكل تصبح ألغازاً
and obstacles disappear.
وتختفي العقبات
When faced with particularly difficult
وعندما نواجه بصعوبة محددة
setbacks or complexities,
انتكاسات أو تعقيدات
a really interesting behavior emerges: decoration.
يظهر سلوك مثير للإهتمام بالفعل: الديكور
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Decoration of the unfinished project
الديكور لمشروع غير منتهي
is a kind of conceptual incubation.
هو نوع من حضانة المفاهيم
From these interludes come deep insights
من هذه الفواصل تأتي أفكار عميقة
and amazing new approaches to solving the problems
ومقاربات جديدة مدهشة لحل المشاكل
that had them frustrated just moments before.
كانت مُحبطة بالنسبة لهم قبل لحظات فقط
All materials are available for use.
كل المواد متاحة لهم للإستخدام
Even those mundane, hateful, plastic grocery bags
حتى تلك الأمور المملة، المكروهة، أكياس البقالة البلاستيكية
can become a bridge
يمكن أن تصبح جسراً
stronger than anyone imagined.
أقوى مما يتصوره أي شخص
And the things that they build
والأشياء التي يبنوها
amaze even themselves.
تدهش الجميع حتى هم
Video: Three, two, one, go!
فيديو: ثلاثة، أثنان، واحد، إنطلق!
Gever Tulley: A rollercoaster built by seven-year-olds.
قيفر توللي: مركبة دوارة بناها طفل عمره سبعة سنوات
Video: Yay!
فيديو: يااي!
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
GT: Thank you. It's been a great pleasure.
قيفر توللي: شكراً لكم. كانت غاية في السرور